Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
They're sand dragons.
Watch carefully, Nol.
The smaller ones are tagging along, aren't they ?
We'll exterminate the entire swarm.
Gatlantis lives are artificial.
Unlike humans and other species,
we've thrived through cloning.
You'll eventually succeed to my name and fleet.
You'll be Goland the 20th.
Your DNA is identical to the first generation.
Do you understand what it means, Nol ?
There's no such thing as love,
it's just an irrational emotion.
I've raised and trained you
for the sole purpose...
...of Goland continuing to serve the Gatlantis Empire.
Keep in mind that we are pure.
Therefore we are strong.
But it's natural for living things
to care for their own offspring.
That's egoism...
...self-love, which should be despised,
because it serves no purpose to the whole.
Eventually, you'll fight your first battle.
Soon, you'll succeed to Goland,
and receive a new Nol.
I look forward to it.
Therefore, we are...
Who are you ?
You were an assistant to Professor Redrowz, but you didn't know him for very long.
Your original plan was to join him
on the 11th Planet to investigate Stravase.
In other words, anyone could
have impersonated Katsuragi Touko.
Even a non-Earthling.
Examination results show that
she's human, just like Garmillas and us.
So she's neither a Gatlantis nor a
revived human from a deceased Earthling.
How can you be so sure ?
Because she's alive.
She didn't self-destruct, and became a prisoner.
That's definitely not their mentality.
Regardless of her mission, she would have
been eliminated when her cover was blown.
She has reproductive ability, which is different from
the Gatlantian social structure Kodai was told about.
What is she, really ?
Just before the 11th Planet came under attack, there was massive radar interference, which delayed the military's response.
Was that your doing, as well ?
I've come here because you said you'd talk to me.
Hypocrite.
Is my word wrong ?
We don't have anyone like you.
We ?
A powerless idealist who's
obsessed with unsolvable matters.
What are you talking about ?
You have no such thing
as ideals in your society ?
If you're human...
Sifar Sabera is my real name.
That's it for today, okay ?
Anyway, there'll be no further information leaks.
Is that so ?
We don't know their abilities.
How do we face them...?
You're better off not
getting involved with her.
I was in the intelligence bureau.
I'm used to handling people like her.
Like her ?
They tend to provoke and
manipulate human emotion.
Just don't bother.
As I've explained before, Telezart's sealed inside the rock beds that were brought from elsewhere.
But it's not complete yet.
According to the data sent by Teresa, the last
chunk of rock bed is being transported right now...
...and there's an enemy missile fleet in front of it.
Right behind it is a Telezart
close-support unit near the opening.
So, first and foremost, our assault unit of Cosmo Tiger IIs and
mobile troopers will use the warp booster to position themselves here...
...and confuse the Telezart
close-support unit with our surprise attack.
Warp booster ?
Yeah. It's the device I used
to jump from the Moon.
We can use it one more time.
Only once ?
The booster's a disposable
device used for a single round trip.
In other words, it's a one-way trip,
so you'll come pick us up, right ?
The Yamato will execute a short-range
warp as our assault unit advances...
...and warp out right here behind this huge rock bed.
The rock bed will protect it from the enemy fleet.
But we can't attack them, either.
What are you gonna do ?
We'll use the wave motion gun.
As soon as we warp out, we'll come about 180 degrees and
destroy the rock bed, which should stop the enemy missile fleet.
I see.
You do like to shoot rocks with
the wave motion gun, don't you ?
That'll cover our flanks. Good idea.
But make one mistake, and we'll be
divided into small units and get annihilated.
We must adapt to any circumstance flexibly...
...without being too attached to the original plan.
That said, if we can catch them
off guard, we have a chance to win.
Do your very best.
Tell Goland...
Have you ever been held in someone's arms ?
In your predecessor's arms.
No, never.
I see.
This is your first war.
Learn the true essence of
Gatlantian warfare with your own body.
Sir.
500,000 kilometers to planet Telezart.
Commence the Telezart landing operation.
Don't fall behind because we're not waiting.
Stabilize your posture.
It's different from a fighter.
Designed to wreak-havoc, right ?
Booster connected. All nominal.
Taking off.
Assault unit has warped in.
All hands, prepare for short-range warp.
We're the same kind...
...aren't we ?
I wonder what you did to this ship's engine.
It's okay. I'll keep your secret.
I want to see his face twisted in despair.
Why haven't you told anyone about me ?
You will eventually betray the Yamato.
Betray...
Five seconds to warp.
Four...
...three...
...two...
...one.
Betray who ?
Warp !
Fire all bow torpedoes !
Alright, good work, Tsurumi.
Maintain current speed.
We're gonna kick their ass !
Copy that !
Report from the Telezart close-support unit. The enemy unit is made of a small...
What ?
Mechanized infantry ?!
Not the Yamato ?
Calm down.
We fight a bold but well-prepared war.
We made a strategic move long
before the beginning of this battle.
All ships, turn 180 degrees !
Fire the Arrow of Doom !
That's two down.
Tsurumi, break away.
We don't have much time.
Let me finish you off.
Tsurumi, you're being targeted !
Increase your speed !
Damn, until the Yamato arrives...
Here it comes !
Fire the demolition missile.
Gravitational interference detected !
The interference has affected Telezart's
gravitational field, and created turbulence.
Anti-matter...?!
That missile was filled with
energy extracted from Telezart.
It has some interesting effects.
Yamato detected.
Let's finish the hunt.
Shouldn't the fleet spread out a little ?
If the ships are so close to each other,
when the Yamato fires its big gun...
It can't take aim in that turbulence.
Besides, they won't use it.
They can't.
Get us out of here ! Chief !
Wave motion engine, maximum output.
Wait.
If we leave this turbulence, we'll be an easy target.
The operation is still underway.
Prepare to fire the wave motion gun.
We'll use this turbulence to our advantage,
and calculate the best line of fire to the enemy fleet.
We'll fire the wave motion gun
directly at the enemy fleet !
Look, they're bound by an unreasonable
emotion called love, so they can't shoot us.
What're you going to do ?
Acting Captain, now is the best line of fire to annihilate the enemy fleet in one shot.
This's Saito. Do you copy ?
Pops, if you're on the bridge,
you fire the wave motion gun.
This is ridiculous, but we have no choice.
It's not a matter of reasoning.
He's made a promise to someone very important.
So instead...
No, don't.
This is a burden that everyone who
traveled to Iscandar must bear equally.
The Yamato has no future unless
you break its curse yourself.
Kodai, show your resolve.
Your resolve as a commander.
Open the channel to the wave motion gun.
Opening the channel to the wave motion gun.
Close all emergency valves.
Activate the forced injector.
Release the final safety.
The trigger isn't just yours.
Shima...
I'll shoot, too.
Me too.
All hands, prepare for shock and flash !
Saito, do you copy ?
The ship's unstable because
of the gravitational turbulence.
I need a favor.
I know. Let's do it, guys ?
Do what, Commander ?
Isn't it obvious ?
Push it by hand.
Kodai, I'll accept your offer to be the Captain.
If you have no way out or
solution, you must face it.
Both you and I.
This is everyone's shot !
We all bear the burden.
Unreasonable emotion...because they're human...
Goland, I...
The Yamato has completely stopped moving.
Nol, watch carefully.
This is the end of the battle.
Finish it off !
Large number of missiles incoming.
Ignore them !
Sight locked.
Five seconds till firing !
Four...
...three...
...two...
...one.
Fire !
Sorry, Nol.
It's okay.
Promise me to never repeat our folly.
I promise.
Captain Hijikata, as the Tactical Commander, my concern is the remaining Gatlantis force on the rock bed.
I request that we continue the operation.
Granted.
Coordinate with the Space Cavalry to come up with a plan to use the wave motion excavator.
Aye, sir.
Episode 13
Telezart Landing Operation ? Destroy the Enemy Fleet of Missile Ships !
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo
Kato Saburo:
Yamamoto Akira:
Tsurumi Jiro:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Tanaka Rie
Komoto Keisuke
Togire yuku manazashi wa...
Your fading gaze turns to...
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Okita Juzo:
Hijikata Ryu:
Katsuragi Touko:
Keyman:
Starsia:
Zorder:
Goland:
Nol:
Gatlantis Solder:
Crewman:
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Sugao Takayuki
Ishizuka Unsho
Kaida Yuko
Kamioya Hiroshi
Inoue Kikuko
Tezuka Hideaki
Yamaji Kazuhiro
Hikami Takahiro
Fujinuma Kento
Yano Masaaki
...Yuuja no tashika na rashinban
...a trusted compass of a warrior
Yakusoku wa nai mama ni...
Without any promise...
...Yatsura mo ikari wo agedasu
...they will weigh anchor in response
Kowarekaketa kono sekai wa...
The half-destroyed world has named...
...Te wo sashinoberu hito no na wo
...the people who can lend a hand
Namari iro no kotae ga...
A lead-colored response...
...Kurayami ni tsumetaku tsukihanasu
...cut coldly through the darkness
Inochi wo tsumuide tokoshie no tami
Spin the thread of life for the everlasting journey
Kibou no kuni e
To the nation of hope
Otoko no sadame ni seigi tsuranuki
Stay faithful to justice in men's destiny
Torawareta ashita wo sukuu no sa
Save the besieged future
Shuuen ni mukaeba itsuka rifujin na sekai ga...
When the end comes near, the unexpected world will...
...Kurenai no sakazuki de otagai no yuuki tataeyou
...cheer both sides with a crimson cup
Hakai to souzou densetsu no kake...
Destruction and creation, and legendary wagers...
...Yatsura mo onaji sa
...fall onto both sides
Tatakai no hibuta
The outbreak of war
Towa ni kirarete honou no okite
It repeats endlessly in a destined blaze
Kodoku to shouri ga korogariochiru...
Loneliness and victory will eventually be known...
...Mekuru meku uchuu no hate made
...throughout dazzling space
Preview
What gives them such motivation ?
Here comes the big boss, huh ?
...stole Garmillas technology ?
It's dangerous ! Please evacuate !
Almost.
Believe in Kodai and the others.
We can descend to Terezalium.
Episode 14
Zarvival's Onslaught and the Discovery of Teresa